Curriculum Vitae



Jakub Fiala

Schwedenstraße 16 13357 Berlin Deutschland

phone +49 163 187 5047 mail jakub@fiala.space web fiala.space github jakubfiala

I'm a software engineer and artist with 9 years of experience building interactive and audiovisual applications on both web and native platforms. Interested in social ecology, utopian thinking, domain-driven design and clean & predictable user experiences.

Work history

Jan 2020 - present

Ecosia GmbH

Technical Lead - building a powerful microservice-oriented search platform with modern UI components.

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

Studio Fiala Ltd.

Director - specialising in computational art & audiovisual web technologies consulting

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

British Broadcasting Corporation

Creative Technologist / Web Developer - in the IRFS section of BBC Research & Development.

Sept 2016 – Jan 2018

Wellcome Trust

Senior Software Developer

August 2015 - present

Interactive Web / Audio / Machine

Intelligence Consultant

Clients inc. Greyworld, XL Recordings, Synervoz, etc.

July 2014 - June 2016

Goldsmiths Digital

DSP & Interactive Media Developer

October 2014 – July 2015

KnowledgeRocks Ltd.

iOS/Web Application Developer

Education

2015 - 2016

Goldsmiths, University of London

MSci Creative Computing

2012 - 2015

Goldsmiths, University of London

BSc Music Computing

2010 - 2012

Gymnázium Jura Hronca

International Baccalaureate Diploma

2004 - 2010

Gymnázium Partizánske

Programming Languages & Tools

JavaScript - Vue, React, Three.js, Node.js, Electron

Web Platform - HTML5, modern CSS, SCSS, Canvas, Web Audio, Web GL

Go - gRPC

Python - TensorFlow, NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Flask, Django

PHP - Drupal, WordPress

C++ - OpenFrameworks, Chromium

Databases - Postgres, Redis, MongoDB

Language skills

English – fluent (anglophone – CERF C1)

German - intermediate (CERF B2)

French – intermediate (CERF B2)

Spanish - basic

Czech - fluent

Slovak - native

Selected publications, talks, workshops

Uroboros Festival 2020 Oracles for Troubling Times: Designing new divination systems https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KxmAd6ByK40

Web Audio Conference 2018 *r-audio: Declarative, reactive and flexible Web Audio graphs in React* https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cetQblX3ji4

Sónar+D 2018 Singing with Machines workshop on behalf of BBC Research&Development, delivered with Tim Cowlishaw.

https://sonarplusd.com/en/programs/barcelona-2018/areas/workshops/singing-with- machines

Global Al Hackathon Seoul [2016] I was part of a team from Goldsmiths, University of London at the Global Al Hackathon in Seoul organised by Nabi Art Centre. The hackathon participants included teams from the USA, Germany, China and South Korea. Along with Hadeel Ayoub and Leon Fedden we developed a working prototype of a glove which detects learned hand gestures and translates them into speech using IBM Watson APIs. Our project was awarded the first prize. https://www.gold.ac.uk/news/ai-hackathon-seoul/

International Conference on Live Interfaces 2016 – University of Sussex Publication of the paper "Collaborative coding interfaces on the Web" (written in collaboration with Dr. Mick Grierson and Dr. Matthew Yee-King) in proceedings. http://reframe.sussex.ac.uk/reframebooks/archive2016/live-interfaces/

Web Audio Conference 2015 – IRCAM, Paris Publication of the paper "Meyda: an audio feature extraction library for the Web Audio API" (written in collaboration with H. Rawlinson and N. Segal) in proceedings. https://medias.ircam.fr/x8fbaf8

Selected artworks, performances & exhibitions

Tarot of the Latent Spaces, 2022, exhibited at Vorspiel Berlin, January 2022

Slices of the Ocean, Form 2019, CICA Museum, South Korea, September 2019

Immunotherapy (N. Matsumoto & N. Koetting), Talion Gallery, Tokyo, September 2019

Acheiropoieta, ANTIDEGREE show, Croydon Arts Store, 2019.

Made By Machine: When Al Met the Archive, BBC Four documentary, 2018

Made By Machine: When Al Met the Archive, BBC Four documentary, 2018
Alluvial Sharawadji with Tim Cowlishaw, Eufónic Festival, Catalunya, 2018
The Artist's Rite, performance @ PureGold Festival, London, 2015
Scar Mechanics, score for Ana Mendes' Map Series performance, 2014